Cristian Espinoza

Lead Software Engineer

Krakow, Poland +48 576 850 689 cris.esza@gmail.com

espinoza.cristian

in /cristianarielespinoza

/cristianespinoza

Professional Summary

14+ Years in software / web application development, mostly offshore.

Extensive experience in Front-End technologies, leading teams and people management Fluent in English language (C1+), written and spoken

Development Skills

Front-End Development

- JavascriptEcmascript 7
- CSS3 SASS
- HTML5 XHTML
- Responsive Design Mobile First

- ReactJS, Redux, Saga, Jest, VueJS
- Compilers webpack, babel
- Tools
 Eslint, Gulp,
 Requirejs
- Grid, Flex
 Bootstrap

- Package Managers npm, yarn
- Unit Testing Mocha, Karma
- JQuery Backbone Marionette
- SMACSS BEM

Back-End Development with PHP

- MVC Frameworks Codeigniter, Zend Framework, Laravel
- CMS Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal
- E-commerce Magento, Zencart, opencart

Operations and Quality Assurance

- Versioning Git, SVN, TFS
- MS Project, Gantt
- Integration
 Jenkins, Teamcity
- Jira, Mantis, Trac
- Unit Testing QA Automation
- Agile, Scrum, Kanban

Databases

- Relational Databases
- MySQL, MS SQL
- Data Structures
 Database Design

Architecture

- Systems Analysis
- REST

Design Patterns

Education and Relevant Interests

- Software Engineering, Universidad Tecnológica Nacional
- Programming, Universidad Tecnológica Nacional
- Interested in Algorithms, Data Structures, Delivery Optimization, People Management

Experience

2018 - Present

Epam, Krakow - Lead Software Engineer & Resource Manager

- Leading a team of software engineers, developing solutions orientated to the Construction Industry, using the latest Frontend technologies (React, Node)
- Resource Management work: Interviewing, hiring, promotions, people management, overseeing other developers' career growth.

2017 - 2018

AppDirect, Buenos Aires - Senior Front-End Engineer

- Front-End Javascript Development: ReactJS, Backbone.
- Development of new modules for AppDirect Marketplace.
- Feature Documentation, Technical Design creation.

2013 - 2017

Casablanca Polo, Buenos Aires - Full Stack Programmer

- In-house Comprehensive Development Services: Analysis, Programming, Maintenance of Legacy Systems.
- Development of several modules on Shopping Cart (Magento), and new modules for a product customization application. Development of a POS (Point of Sale) system for day-to-day management.
- Server Management (LAMP Stack)

2010 - 2013

IntermediaSP, Buenos Aires - Full Stack Programmer - Team Leader

- Leading team of developers, PHP development, interviewing candidates.
- Customer-Facing Roles: Project Quotation, Project Management.
- Software Requirement Analysis, Architecture Designer and Lead Developer for several projects including MALBA, Banco Itau.
- Implemented technologies to improve in-house working environment (Version tracking, bug tracking).

2005 - 2010

Truelogic Software Solutions, Buenos Aires - Full Stack Programmer

- PHP Developer, Front-End Developer.
- Programming and Team Leader in several offshore projects. Full-Stack development.
- Customer-Facing Roles: Project Quotation, Project Management.